#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/hamid-farhani (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Engineering Management
Program Management
Cross-functional Team Leadership

# Hamid Farhani

Director, NPI Manufacturing Engineering at Cepheid Palo Alto, California, United States

# Summary

Provided leadership, fast paced, growing startups, NPI and testing hardware.

Operations Director with experience in motivating and leading successful teams. Demonstrated success in operations/ manufacturing/supply chain, project management, and leadership resulting in, product differentiation, improved profitability and increased revenue.

### Specialties:

- · Operations Management
- Supply Chain Management
- New Product Introduction (NPI)
- Manufacturing (Consumer Electronics, Networking, Custom Engineered Systems)
- Cost Reduction
- Project/Program Management
- Manufacturing Business Systems(ERP/MRP/MES/PLM)
- Lean manufacturing
- Quality/ISO systems
- Start ups

# Experience

### Cepheid

2 years 9 months

Director, NPI Manufacturing Engineering March 2023 - Present (7 months)

Sunnyvale, California, United States

Senior Manager, NPI Manufacturing Engineering September 2021 - March 2023 (1 year 7 months)

Manager, NPI Manufacturing Engineering

#### January 2021 - September 2021 (9 months)

Sunnyvale, California, United States

zSpace, Inc.

Sr. Director of Operations

January 2015 - January 2021 (6 years 1 month)

San Francisco Bay Area

Engaging with suppliers, introducing new products, testing for functionality and ensuring proper mechanical, boards and system assemblies. Partnered closely with JDM teams to manage projects through development lifecycle for VR and AR products.

SpiderCloud Wireless, Inc

**Director of Operations** 

April 2012 - January 2015 (2 years 10 months)

Manage supply chain, manufacturing and test engineering. Drive supplier selection process with engineering, supplier measurement processes and contract negotiation strategies.

Interfaced cross functionally with engineering, product management, finance and other departments.

Manage production cost reduction, leading inventory strategies and inventory management programs.

Completed ISO9001 certifications and quality management system.

GreenVolts

**Director of Operations** 

July 2011 - April 2012 (10 months)

Fremont, CA

Manage Power Systems Operations and Supply Chain. NPI, Testing and Production. Managing contract manufacturing locally and in Asia.

Ericsson

Senior Project Manager

August 2010 - June 2011 (11 months)

San Jose

Managed complete product life cycle projects from concept to production with \$10M budget. Led engineering teams to deliver program milestones on time, within budget and high quality. Ability to proactively identify and resolve problems expeditiously. Provided project detail schedule, estimated effort, total prototypes, CAPEX and expense budget. Managed core team agenda, action items, risks, issues and provided mitigation plans. Successfully managed Page 2 of 6

and supported multiple software/hardware projects and teams. Each project endured 24 months – 30 months. Manage at least 4 projects simultaneously. Managed approximately 18 – 20 team members including marketing, design engineer, NPI, supply chain, quality and for each project in various global locations throughout North America, Europe and Asia.

#### **ALCATEL - LUCENT**

Senior Program Manager May 2006 - August 2010 (4 years 4 months)

Resolved Contract Manufacturing and Original Design Manufacturing (ODM) technical issues to deliver products on time with high quality Lead R & D, Operations, and SQA teams to deliver program milestones on time with high quality.

Committed to total project schedule, and budget of \$4M - \$5M.

Lead engineering teams to deliver program milestones on time with high quality.

Provided project detail schedule, estimated effort, total prototypes, CAPEX and expense budget.

Managed core team agenda, action items, risks, issues and provided mitigation plans.

Successfully managed and supported multiple projects and teams.

Each project endured 18 months - 2 years. Managed at least 3 projects simultaneously.

Managed approximately 10 - 12 team members including program managers, marketing, design engineer, supply chain, quality and for each project in various global locations throughout North America, Europe and Asia.

#### **NetDevices**

Global Operations / Manufacturing Director December 2003 - May 2006 (2 years 6 months)

Managed all engineering and technical aspects of the operations team.

Managed new product introduction throughout entire Product Life Cycle, to assure all product development goals were met at each phase.

Successfully managed and supported multiple projects and teams.

Worked closely R & D, SQA, Customer support teams to ensure high quality products delivered on time.

Set up, support supply chain worldwide to minimize product cost, reduce inventory and defects.

Took ownership of schedule, quality and cost.

#### MCDATA CORP

Operations / Manufacturing Director January 2001 - January 2003 (2 years 1 month)

Managed operations and all technical engineering aspects to support SAN Switch product delivery on time with high quality.

Worked closely R & D, SQA, Customer Support and Product

Management teams to ensure high quality products delivery on time.

Managed ASIC suppliers from FAB, assembly and test.

Supported Marketing and Sales teams for RFQ activities.

Provided total program business cost, operations costs, gross margin and cumulative profit.

Managed strategic suppliers and distributors to reduce lead times and cost.

#### ANDA Networks

Operations / Manufacturing Director January 1998 - January 2001 (3 years 1 month)

Managed operations and all technical engineering aspects to support the product delivery on time with high quality.

Worked closely with hardware, software development and product management to ensure delivery on time with high quality.

Developed and implemented systems for Build-To-Order processes at External Manufacturing operations to reduce and maintain total raw material and finished goods inventory to less than \$0.25M at all time.

Managed and supported global supply chain and contract manufacture. Provided total program business cost, operations costs, gross margin and cumulative profit.

#### **NETPOWER NETWORKS**

Manufacturing Engineering Manager January 1995 - January 1998 (3 years 1 month)

Managed engineering and all technical aspects of operations team to support the product delivery on time with high quality.

Provided transition of consumer products from development to high volume manufacturing.

Implemented technical procedures and processes to improve design and manufacturability

Provided technical support for in-house production line and customer support.

Provided product configurations, structure bill of materials, Engineering

Change Orders.

Provided total program business cost, operations costs, gross margin and cumulative profit.

Managed supplier quality activities and implement processes for First Article Inspection, Source Inspection and Supplier Corrective Action.

ERICSSON, (formerly Raynet)

Senior Manufacturing Engineering
January 1991 - January 1995 (4 years 1 month)

Provided and supported new product introduction for the Voice / Data equipment.

Implemented DFM guidelines for manufacturing to reduce cost, improve manufacturing first pass yield.

Provided technical support and solve issues for in-house production line and test engineering.

Supported product configurations, structured bill of materials, Engineering Change Orders.

Provided total program business cost, operations costs, gross margin and cumulative profit.

#### SUNDSTRAND DATA CONTROL

Senior Manufacturing Engineering January 1987 - January 1991 (4 years 1 month)

Implemented new process techniques, DFM guidelines to reduce cost, improve manufacturing first pass yield.

Supported new product introduction, worked closely with hardware and manufacturing team.

Provided technical support for PCB fabrications, sheet metals and board assemblies.

### Education

Weber State University BS, MS, System Engineering

Weber State University
BS, Manufacturing Engineering

# **Activity**

09/13/2023, Viewed by Joeri Leemans